# M G Preethi

mpreethi2312@gmail.com

+91 7989322593

### **Profile**

Experienced Software Developer with 4 years of experience in Telecom and Banking domains. Enthusiastic team player dedicated to contributing to company success with a proactive learning mindset. Demonstrates strong problem-solving skills and a proven track record in developing and maintaining mission-critical applications. Committed to excellence in software development and driving innovation.

### Education

2016/07 – 2020/05 Tirupati, India	Sree Vidyanikethan Engineering College Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology Graduated with Distinction, Percentage: 80%
2014/06 – 2016/04 Tirupati, India	Narayana Sri Chaithanya Junior College Qualified with distinction, Percentage: 94.3%
2013/06 – 2014/04 Tirupati, India	Narayana Concept School Qualified with distinction, CGPA- 9.7/10

#### **Technical Skills**

- · C, Java
- Spring Boot, MicroServices, JUnit
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- MySQL
- Jenkins, Git, Postman, Jira, SonarQube, Confluence, Bitbucket, pgAdmin

### Work Experience

2022/07 – present Hyderabad, India

### Software Development Engineer

Brillio Technologies

- Project Name: Virtual Network Service Platform (VNSP)
- Client Name: Verizon
- Technologies: Java, SpringBoot, Microservices, Junit, MySQL
- Tools: STS
- **Description:** To automate the Deployment of VNF's using VNSP. This project is related to virtualizing the orchestration of various Network Functions. We do have four deployment models Premise, Hosted, Azure and AWS. Our team mostly works on Premise and Hosted.
- **Responsibilities:** To develop some API's and enhancing based on requirements using Java, SpringBoot.
- Developed Major code in S3 feature.
- Responsible to have discussions with the client to understand the requirements and to provide the appropriate ideas and use cases for implementation of feature.
- Worked on writing Junit to improve the code coverage.
- Involved in debugging and fixing of production issues.
- Worked on fixing Blackduck and Fortify Vulnerabilities. And also worked on fixing issues reported in Sonar Scan.
- Conducted knowledge transfer sessions for new hires.
- Participated in all the aspects of software development life cycle, starting from project conceptualization, iteration through refinement, testing, deployment, and maintenance.

2020/08 - 2022/07 Chennai, India

### **Programmer Analyst**

Cognizant Technology Solutions

- Project Name: Natural Application Processing System(NAPS)
- Technologies: Java, SpringBoot, MySQL, Microservices
- Tools: IntelliJ
- **Description:** NAPS application is used to store all the entitlements. It is connected to an entirex server. It gives us all the details of the user entitlements. By using this application, we can update, delete, add the entitlements based on the requirement.
- **Responsibilities:** Responsible for analysis, design and development of various features using Java.
- Involved in bug fixing/functionality issues.
- Contributed in testing phase and involved in deployment activities.

2019/12 - 2020/06 Chennai, India

#### Intern

Cognizant Technology Solutions

- Completed internal certification in Java, Spring Boot and Spring MVC.
- Developed projects like Online Tailoring System and Employee Management System using Java and SpringBoot.
- Qualified in various code challenges conducted as a part of internship.

# **Academic Projects**

### 1. Baby monitoring System using IOT

Software: Embedded C, Arduino Complier, BLYNK android application

Hardware: Sound sensor, Soil Moisture Sensor, Speaker, Transformer 12v/1Amp, Capacitor, Relay, Bread

board, Node MCU

**Description:** IOT based baby monitoring system has introduced which works efficiently in real time. The mic in the system detects the babies cry and performs the action accordingly as provided, like playing songs and sending alert to the registered user email so that they can keep track about their baby. It also detects the wetness using Soil Moisture Sensor and sends the alert to register users through Blynk application.

### 2. Haircut and spa booking system

Technologies: Java, html, jsp, CSS, Spring, PHP.

**Description**: The project is once the user registers in Salon App, user will be listed with the list of services and their cost. Customer can choose their desired service and book a slot for the service based on the availability. The Application will also provide list of items used for a specific service and what is the process being followed.

## **Training & Certifications**

- Completed the training on Cloud Services with AWS conducted by APSSDC.
- Participated in Skill Development Program on Advanced Data Science Tools conducted by Department of Information Technology, Sree Vidyanikethan Engineering College.
- Certified on SAFe for Teams Course.
- Completed Introduction to Cybersecurity through edX.
- Successfully Completed C test organized at Sree Vidyanikethan Engineering College with Course material provided by the Talk To A Teacher project at IIT Bombay.

### Volunteer Experience

2018/10 - 2019/11

### **Event Coordination and Conduction, SVEC Tirupati**

Worked as an organizer and coordinator in Mohana Mantra, technical fest of SVEC Tirupati.

### **Extra-Curriculars**

Won prizes in various events: Poetry, Essay writing, Music and Quiz Competitions.